hello and thank you for watching this
video on the Manulife premium protection
plan and allowing us to explain the main
feature that it offers under the premium
protection plan it has a cancel for any
reason clause where you can cancel seven
days and more before the departure date
and Manulife will pay up to 75 percent
of the covered amount for the prepaid
portion of your trip that is
non-refundable if your to cancel between
six days and as little as 24 hours
before the departure date manual 8 will
pay up to 75% of the coverage amount for
the prepaid portion of your trip that is
non-refundable up to a maximum $1500
let's clarify trip cancellation
interruption and what is considered an
unexpected event an unexpected event is
any sudden and unforeseen reason event
causing the cancellation impacting the
ability to travel as planned now the
differences between unexpected event and
an expected event is in this
clarification for an unexpected event
any sudden and unforeseen reason event
causing the consolation impacting the
ability to travel as planned for example
David needs hip surgery surgery will be
scheduled six to twelve months from
today David books a trip for next month
he receives a call from a surgeon
advising his surgery date has been moved
up to an earlier date and now conflicts
with this trip now an example of an
expected event is David needs hip
surgery surgery will be scheduled within
three months
David books the trip for next month he
receives a call from his surgeon
advising his confirmed surgery date
which now conflicts with this trip so
that's pretty much the difference
between an unexpected and a expect
[Music]
so let's explain some scenarios here a
client is traveling to Europe and part
of the retainer includes a visit to
Paris there is a terrorist attack in
Paris after the client booked their trip
client longer feels confident to travel
can the client cancel and the answer is
yes under the premium protection plan
the client is covered up to 100% because
the clients cancellation is unexpected
and is not excluded now under the
inclusive plan the client is not covered
unless the Government of Canada issues
and avoid non-essential travel or avoid
all travel travel advisor after your
client purchases their insurance
advising or recommending that a Canadian
resident should not visit a destination
included in their trip now under
scenario 2 the client is traveling to
Europe to visit London in room
there is a terrorist attack in Paris
after the client booked their trip claim
no longer feels confident to travel can
the client cancel the client will be
covered under the counsel for any reason
as there is no terrorist attack in
either the cities on their itinerary so
under the premium protection plan the
clients covered up to 75% of the covered
amount under the standard all-inclusive
plan the client is only covered up to
50% of the covered amount now is
scenario 3 the client sites anxiety and
seeks medical attention regarding this
London trip due to concerns stemming
from the Paris attack client submits the
attending physician statement confirming
a medical diagnosis of anxiety can the
client pencil the answer is yes under
the premium protection plan the client
is covered up to 100% because the
clients cancellation is due to an
unforeseen medical condition which would
be considered a covered event under the
standard all-inclusive plan though the
covers would only be 50% because the
the option cancel using this benefit
with this scenario mandatory cheerleader
practices announce after your client
books their trip to Mexico can the
client canceled and the answer is under
the premium protection plan yes coverage
is 100% because the clients cancellation
is due to an unexpected event which
would be considered a cover event under
the basic all-inclusive plan though
coverage would only be 50% in this
scenario of 33 old books an
all-inclusive trip to Cuban purchases
the premium protection plan when booking
the trip this client is an avid football
fan and when his favorite team makes it
to the Super Bowl which occurs during
his trip dates he is torn as he would
rather watch the football game at home
than be away on vacation can the client
cancel yes the client will be covered
under the counsel for any reason
coverage and if he cancels seven days
before the trip he will be reimbursed up
to 75% of this prepaid travel
arrangements so under the premium
protection plan and 75% is covered of
the amount under this standard
all-inclusive plan though only 50% is
covered that's pretty much the
difference between and the explanation
of the premium protection plan if you do
have any more questions on this
particular coverage please feel free to
contact us directly you can phone us at
2:04 - and nine four - five four or
email us at info at the traveling agency
a again thank you for watching this
video on the clarification of the
premium protection plan and we look
forward to hearing from you soon